

Jamie Davies

Full Stack Developer

Mobile: 07718061934 - Portfolio: <u>iamjamiedavies.com</u>

Summary

I'm a full stack developer who's great at building beautiful functional products from the ground up, alone or as part of a team. I started programming at the age of 8, and at 14 I founded my first funded start-up.

I have a massive passion for hackathons, which has given me ability to work with and learn new technologies, while at the same time rapidly building awesome prototypes. I have recently left my start-up, to branch out and gain more experience doing different things.

I also **love** data, my current position at TalkLife has given me access to a wealth of rich data that i've been able to do incredibly fun, but also useful things with. These includes building a real-time trend analysis visualisation using the 3 million+ posts in talklife to spot trends topics in the community.

Experience

Co-Founder and Developer

Doorpass

2016 - Current

Doorpass is a cloud management solution for managing your employees and their permissions on external cloud services. I've been working on it as a side project with a friend since March '16

- Built a modular scalable integration system that standardises user management APIs across many different platforms.
- Built automated scraper bots to manage sub-users on external platforms that don't expose a public API for managing users

Developer

TalkLife 2015 - Current

 Built a confidential messaging service that connects patients to licensed therapists for a low monthly cost

- Designed and built an admin/overview dashboard that views and controls all the different TalkLife related services
- I come up with and prototype new ideas, using different technologies to test their feasibility and demo to investors.
- I help out with Growth Hacking, Project Management, Quality Assurance testing and other administrative work.
- Worked alongside bright minds at MIT, Harvard and Microsoft Research to work on an incredible research project involving mental health and suicide intervention.
- Built multiple internal tools used in processing large amounts of data to assist in tasks like moderation and suicide intervention.

Co-Founder and Development

whatleads.to (former CauseHub.io)

2013 - 2015

- Founded in December 2013 and pitched to receive incubator funding from Bethnal Green Ventures.
- Built a scalable web app and API able to handle thousands of concurrent connections.
- Built the entire back-end and dynamic front-end codebase to work on the distributed infrastructure while keeping load times and bandwidth low
- (Ref: Sanjay Poyzer, +44 789 512 3673, sanjay@whatleads.to)

Waiter

The Rotisserie

2012 - 2015

- Working at my fathers restaurant on the service floor as a Waiter, responsible for taking orders, interacting with customers, resolving problems and preparing desserts.
- (Ref: Ian Davies, +44 773 674 1314, ian@therotisserie.co.uk)

Intern

Innovation Warehouse

Summer 2013

- Summer internship / work experience at a co-working space.
- Worked on the website and also every day administrative work around the office.
- Worked with multiple startups on helping test their ideas and resolve problems in the workspace.
- Assisted with organising and running events with 100+ attendees
- Helped maintain and improve the large and complex network

Freelance Admin Work

Comotion

Helping with administrative work

Summer 2013

Education Mill Hill School

GCSEs

Computer Science A*

Maths A

Statistics A

Separate Science (Physics, Biology, Chemistry) A B C

Design Technology A

English C

AS-Levels (Ceiling grade A)

Computer Science A Maths A Physics A (predicted) Design Technology B

A2-Levels (This year)

Computer Science A* (Predicted) Maths A* (Predicted) Physics A (Predicted)

Achievements Work

- Built a start-up at the age of 14, which received investments, grants and multiple awards, as well as media attention on The Guardian and the BBC One Show.
- First year winner of the Duke of York's IDEA award for young entrepreneurs
- Worked alongside the bright minds at MIT, Harvard and Microsoft Research on a world first research project involving mental health and suicide intervention.

Other Activities

- Volunteered in a school in Southern India for 3 weeks over summer 2016 teaching conversational english to underprivileged kids from a local rural town
- A keen cricketer, scuba diver, photographer, climber and office ping pong star.
- Currently training for a private pilot license as i've always had a passion for planes and aviation